<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[NorthCalfrenchies]]></title><description><![CDATA[WE LOVE FRENCH BULLDOGS! 
THAT'S WHY WE (NORTHCALFRENCHIES) 
WANT TO HELP PEOPLE IN CA, OR, WA, ID, NV ADOPT,  REHOME, AND CARE FOR FRENCHIES.]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/frenchbulldogblog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:09:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Are French Bulldogs Aggressive? Understanding Frenchie Behaviour.]]></title><description><![CDATA[French Bulldogs are beloved for their adorable appearance and friendly demeanor, but like any dog breed, they can exhibit aggressive...]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/are-french-bulldogs-aggressive-understanding-frenchie-behaviour</link><guid isPermaLink="false">64efb5a1274b3d9b575e136d</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 21:49:24 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_9a3f4646c3394c9393f197491780b40c~mv2.webp/v1/fit/w_760,h_507,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong><em>French Bulldogs are beloved for their adorable appearance and friendly demeanor, but like any dog breed, they can exhibit aggressive behavior under certain circumstances. While Frenchies are generally known for their calm and affectionate nature, it's essential to understand the factors that can contribute to aggression in these lovable companions. In this comprehensive guide, we'll explore the signs of aggression in French Bulldogs, the potential causes, and effective strategies for prevention and management.</em></strong></p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_9a3f4646c3394c9393f197491780b40c~mv2.webp/v1/fit/w_760,h_507,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>The French Bulldog Temperament: A Gentle and Loving Breed</strong></p>

<p>French Bulldogs have gained a reputation as excellent family pets due to their calm and collected temperament. They thrive on human companionship, and their happiest moments are when they are showered with love and affection. Frenchies are typically known for their friendly and sociable nature, making them ideal companions for families of all sizes.</p>
<p>
However, it's crucial to remember that individual personality traits and environmental factors can influence a dog's behavior, regardless of breed. While French Bulldogs are generally not aggressive by nature, it's essential to be aware of potential signs of aggression and take proactive measures to prevent any unwarranted incidents.</p>
<p>
<strong>Signs of Aggression in French Bulldogs</strong></p>

<p>French Bulldogs, like any other breed, can display several signs of aggression. It's crucial to recognize these signs early on to address any potential issues effectively. Here are some common indicators that your Frenchie may be exhibiting aggressive behavior:</p>
<p>
<strong>1. Disobedience: A Stubborn Streak</strong></p>

<p>French Bulldogs are known for their stubbornness, which can sometimes make training a challenge. While disobedience alone does not necessarily indicate aggression, it can be a precursor to more concerning behaviors. If your Frenchie consistently resists training and displays a lack of obedience, it's essential to address this behavior promptly to prevent aggression from developing.</p>
<p>
<strong>2. Growling: Vocalizing Discomfort or Fear</strong></p>

<p>Growling is a common form of communication for dogs, often indicating feelings of fear, discomfort, or territoriality. If your French Bulldog growls at you, another pet, or a person, it's crucial to understand the underlying trigger and address it appropriately. Responding with positive reinforcement and seeking professional guidance can help curb this behavior and promote a more harmonious environment.</p>
<p>
<strong>3. Snapping: A Warning Sign</strong></p>

<p>Snapping is a more severe form of aggression often displayed when a dog feels threatened, hurt, or agitated. If your Frenchie progresses from growling to snapping, it's vital to intervene promptly to prevent the behavior from escalating further. Teaching bite inhibition and providing appropriate chew toys can help redirect their behavior and discourage snapping.</p>
<p>
<strong>4. Body Language: Unveiling Emotional State</strong></p>

<p>A dog's body language can provide valuable insights into their emotional state and potential for aggression. Pay attention to signs such as a stiffened tail, bared teeth, raised hackles (hair on the back of the neck), tense body posture, and intense staring. If you notice any combination of these signs in your French Bulldog, it's essential to remove them from the situation and address their emotional needs.</p>
<p>
<strong>5. Jealousy: Protectiveness Over Resources</strong></p>

<p>French Bulldogs, like many dogs, can experience jealousy, particularly when it comes to attention from their owners. Signs of jealousy in Frenchies may include barking, growling, or even snapping when another person or pet receives attention. It's crucial to establish boundaries and reinforce positive behavior to prevent jealousy from escalating into aggression.</p>
<p>
<strong>6. Strong Demand for Attention and Affection: Balancing Boundaries</strong></p>

<p>French Bulldogs have a natural desire for attention and affection. While this trait is endearing, it can sometimes lead to aggressive behavior if their demands are not met. Some Frenchies may resort to nipping or barking to gain attention. Teaching them alternative ways to communicate their needs, such as sitting calmly or using a designated mat, can help prevent aggression stemming from attention-seeking behaviors.</p>
<p>
<strong>7. Excessive Barking: Fear and Anxiety
</strong></p>
<p>Excessive barking can be a sign of fear, anxiety, or territoriality, all of which can contribute to aggression. French Bulldogs with separation anxiety may bark excessively when left alone, while fear of unfamiliar situations or people can trigger defensive aggression. Identifying the underlying cause and implementing positive reinforcement training can help reduce excessive barking and mitigate aggressive tendencies.</p>

<p><strong>8. Desire for Dominance: Establishing Hierarchy</strong></p>

<p>French Bulldogs, particularly males, may exhibit a desire for dominance within their social group. This behavior can escalate into aggression, especially in dogs that have not received adequate impulse control training or socialization. Early training and proper socialization can help prevent dominant behaviors from developing into more aggressive tendencies.</p>
<p>
<strong>9. Fear or Anxiety: Unraveling the Root Causes</strong></p>

<p>Like humans, dogs can experience fear and anxiety that can manifest as aggressive behavior. Separation anxiety is a common issue among French Bulldogs, leading to destructive behaviors and potential aggression. Addressing underlying anxiety through training, exercise, and environmental enrichment can help alleviate fear-based aggression.</p>

<p><strong>Preventing and Managing Aggression in French Bulldogs</strong></p>

<p>Prevention and early intervention are key when it comes to managing aggression in French Bulldogs. Here are some effective strategies to ensure your Frenchie remains a well-behaved and sociable companion:</p>

<p><strong>1. Proper Training: Establishing Boundaries</strong></p>

<p>Consistent and positive reinforcement-based training is essential for all dogs, including French Bulldogs. By establishing clear boundaries and teaching basic obedience commands, you can help prevent aggressive behaviors from developing. Enrolling your Frenchie in puppy training classes or working with a professional dog trainer can provide the guidance needed to establish a solid foundation of obedience and manners.</p>
<p>
<strong>2. Socialization: Building Confidence</strong></p>

<p>Early and ongoing socialization is crucial for French Bulldogs to develop confidence and positive associations with other animals and people. Exposing your Frenchie to various environments, sounds, and experiences from a young age can help reduce the likelihood of fear-based aggression. Controlled and positive interactions with other dogs and humans can foster social skills and prevent aggressive behavior.</p>
<p>
<strong>3. Environmental Enrichment: Keeping Your Frenchie Happy</strong></p>

<p>Providing a stimulating environment is essential for preventing boredom and anxiety in French Bulldogs. Interactive toys, puzzle feeders, and regular exercise can help channel their energy and prevent the development of aggressive behaviors. Mental stimulation through training sessions and enrichment activities also contributes to a well-balanced and content Frenchie.</p>
<p>
<strong>4. Positive Reinforcement: Rewarding Good Behavior</strong></p>

<p>Positive reinforcement is a powerful tool for shaping desirable behaviors in French Bulldogs. Rewarding your Frenchie for displaying good behavior, such as obeying commands or interacting calmly with others, reinforces their positive associations and encourages them to continue exhibiting those behaviors. Treats, praise, and playtime can all be effective rewards for your Frenchie's good behavior.</p>
<p>
<strong>5. Veterinary Support: Addressing Health Concerns</strong></p>

<p>Certain health conditions can contribute to aggression in French Bulldogs. It's crucial to maintain regular veterinary check-ups to rule out any underlying medical issues that may be causing discomfort or pain. Conditions such as allergies, ear infections, and spinal disorders can affect a Frenchie's behavior and contribute to aggression. Your veterinarian can provide guidance on managing these health concerns to promote a more balanced and secure Frenchie.</p>
<p>
<strong>6. Professional Guidance: Seeking Expert Advice</strong></p>

<p>If you're struggling to manage your Frenchie's aggressive behavior or have concerns about their temperament, seeking professional guidance from a certified dog behaviorist or trainer can be invaluable. These experts can assess the specific causes of aggression and develop a tailored behavior modification plan to address your Frenchie's needs effectively.</p>

<p>If you choose to take your furry family member to dog training school. We would love to recommend this online <a href="https://k9ti.org/r/maxgonchar/free-workshop/" target="_blank" >,<u>K9 Training Institute</u></a>. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_d5888ed9bc344c3f85eae2ef568cc497~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_400,h_273,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>
<strong>Conclusion</strong></p>

<p>While French Bulldogs are not typically aggressive, it's essential to remain vigilant and address any signs of aggression promptly. Understanding the potential causes of aggression and implementing preventive measures, such as proper training, socialization, and environmental enrichment, can help ensure a well-behaved and sociable Frenchie. Additionally, considering alternative breeds like the Royal Frenchel can provide a calm and cooperative companion with improved overall health. By taking proactive steps and seeking professional guidance when necessary, you can foster a loving and harmonious relationship with your French Bulldog or another compatible breed. So, embrace the journey of understanding and nurturing your Frenchie's unique personality, and enjoy the many joys that come with being a responsible and loving dog owner.</p>

<p>Learn more about french bulldogs on our French Bulldog FAQ Tab:</p>
 <p>Or visit the American Kennel Club and learn more about this wonderful dog breed.</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Keep Your French Bulldog's Wrinkles Clean and Healthy]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you are a proud owner of a French Bulldog, you know that their adorable squished and wrinkly face is one of their most endearing...]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/how-to-keep-your-french-bulldog-s-wrinkles-clean-and-healthy</link><guid isPermaLink="false">64dbc54af0533743f2b9113f</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 18:55:02 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_9513bd1f187c4d8691fe8b725f55dca6~mv2.webp/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>If you are a proud owner of a French Bulldog, you know that their adorable squished and wrinkly face is one of their most endearing features. However, those cute face wrinkles require regular cleaning and a little TLC. Face wrinkles provide a dark and moist environment, which is perfect for bacteria and yeast to grow. Cleaning your Frenchie's wrinkles is not only a matter of hygiene but also essential to prevent infections and keep your furry friend happy and healthy.</strong></em></p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_9513bd1f187c4d8691fe8b725f55dca6~mv2.webp/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Why Cleaning Your French Bulldog's Wrinkles is Important?</strong></p>

<p>French Bulldogs, like other breeds with wrinkles, are prone to skin issues due to the folds and creases in their skin. The folds create a warm and damp environment, which can lead to the accumulation of dirt, debris, and moisture. This, in turn, creates the ideal conditions for bacteria and yeast to thrive, potentially causing infections, irritation, and unpleasant odors. Regular cleaning of your Frenchie's wrinkles helps prevent these issues and promotes their overall well-being.</p>


<p><strong>How Often Should You Clean Your French Bulldog's Wrinkles?</strong></p>

<p>It is recommended to clean your Frenchie's wrinkles and folds at least once a week. However, some Frenchies may require daily cleaning, depending on their individual needs. Factors such as the depth of the wrinkles, the amount of discharge or eye goo, and any existing skin conditions can influence the frequency of cleaning. Observing your Frenchie's wrinkles regularly and adjusting the cleaning routine accordingly will help keep them healthy and happy.</p>

<a href="https://youtu.be/uRtSdwY49fM">https://youtu.be/uRtSdwY49fM</a><p><strong>Step-by-Step Guide to Cleaning Your French Bulldog's Wrinkles</strong></p>

<p>Follow these easy steps to effectively clean your French Bulldog's wrinkles and keep them in top condition:</p>

<p><strong>Step 1: Prepare for Cleaning</strong></p>
<p>Before you begin cleaning your Frenchie's wrinkles, make sure to wash your hands thoroughly. Clean hands are essential to prevent the introduction of bacteria or other contaminants to your dog's sensitive skin. After cleaning, gather all the necessary supplies, including unscented grooming wipes or a soft cloth and warm water.</p>

<p>Grooming wipes : </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_1d1ef9c7b9b04ba2b28c31eeea0bb2a1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_690,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>
<strong>Step 2: Gently Wipe the Face Wrinkles</strong></p>
<p>Take a grooming wipe or a soft cloth dampened with warm water and gently wipe the face wrinkles, removing any debris, dirt, or eye discharge. It is important to be gentle during this process to avoid causing any discomfort or irritation to your Frenchie. Use a different wipe or section of the cloth for each wrinkle to prevent cross-contamination.</p>


<p><strong>Step 3: Dry the Wrinkles Thoroughly</strong></p>
<p>After cleaning, take a clean cloth or tissue and gently pat dry the wrinkles. Moisture left in the folds can create a breeding ground for bacteria and yeast, leading to skin irritations and infections. Make sure to dry all the wrinkles thoroughly to prevent any potential issues.</p>

<p><strong>Step 4: Consider Using a Wrinkle Cream</strong></p>
<p>If your French Bulldog is prone to tear stains or has particularly sensitive skin, you may want to consider using a wrinkle cream specifically formulated for Bulldogs. Products like Squishface Wrinkle Paste or Two Pets and a Half Wrinkle Cream can help clean and protect your dog's wrinkles and folds. Consult with your veterinarian to find the most suitable option for your Frenchie.</p>

<p>Wrinkle Cream: </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_c523eca7300d40e197289665023730f4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_607,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Step 5: Moisturize Dry Wrinkles (if necessary)</strong></p>
<p>If you notice that your Frenchie's wrinkles are dry or flaky, you can apply a small amount of Vaseline or coconut oil to moisturize the skin. Be cautious not to overapply or use products that are not safe for dogs. Always consult with your veterinarian before introducing any new products to your pet's skincare routine.</p>

<p><strong>Step 6: Don't Forget the "Tail Pocket"</strong></p>
<p>Some French Bulldogs have a fold underneath their tail, commonly known as a "tail pocket." This area requires special attention and cleaning to prevent infection and discomfort. Use the same method described above to clean the tail pocket, ensuring that it remains dry and free from debris.</p>

<p><strong>Step 7: Watch for Signs of Infection</strong></p>
<p>Even with regular cleaning, it's important to keep an eye out for any signs of infection in your Frenchie's wrinkles. Redness, inflammation, discharge, an unpleasant odor, or dry and itchy areas may indicate an underlying issue. If you notice any of these symptoms or have concerns about your dog's skin health, consult with your veterinarian for proper diagnosis and treatment.</p>

<p>Anti-Yeast Spray: </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_e035e352a5bc4ed588a3dbd2817b9c09~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_358,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Wrinkle Cleaning Tips for Other Wrinkle-Prone Dog Breeds</strong></p>

<p>While this guide focuses on French Bulldogs, many other dog breeds with wrinkles may benefit from a similar cleaning routine. English Bulldogs, Pugs, Mastiffs, Boston Terriers, Basset Hounds, and Shar-Peis are just a few examples of breeds that require regular wrinkle care. Adapt the steps and products mentioned in this article to suit the specific needs of your dog's breed.</p>

<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>Keeping your French Bulldog's wrinkles clean and healthy is an essential part of their overall care. Regular cleaning helps prevent infections, irritation, and unpleasant odors, ensuring your Frenchie stays happy and comfortable. By following the step-by-step guide provided in this article, you can maintain your dog's wrinkles in top condition. Remember to consult with your veterinarian for personalized advice and recommendations, and enjoy the adorable and unique features of your wrinkly-faced companion!</p>


<p>Subscribe to our newsletter for more tips and information on Frenchie care and well-being!</p>

 <p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> I am not a veterinarian, just a dedicated Frenchie lover. The information in this article is not intended to replace professional veterinary advice. Always consult with a qualified veterinarian for guidance specific to your pet's needs.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[10 WAYS - How To Keep French Bulldogs Cool And Prevent Overheating. ]]></title><description><![CDATA[10 WAYS - How To Keep French Bulldogs Cool And Prevent Overheating. ]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/10-ways-how-to-keep-french-bulldogs-cool-and-prevent-overheating</link><guid isPermaLink="false">64d0643f8106002eaf8c0798</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 03:53:54 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_717f693a7e9d45f99c79d2202e32d7fd~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_801,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>French Bulldogs are undeniably charming, but their short-nosed structure makes them susceptible to overheating. As responsible pet owners, it's essential to understand the reasons behind their vulnerability and take proactive measures to keep them cool and safe. In this article, we present ten effective ways to ensure your beloved French Bulldog stays comfortable and happy during hot weather.</em></strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_717f693a7e9d45f99c79d2202e32d7fd~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_801,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="French Bulldog drinking" alt="French Bulldog drinking from water bottle."></figure><p><strong>Understanding Overheating in French Bulldogs</strong></p>

<p><strong>Brachycephalic Breeds and Heat Sensitivity:</strong> French Bulldogs' short snouts make it challenging for them to regulate body temperature effectively. Unlike dogs with longer snouts, they struggle to cool themselves efficiently through panting.</p>

<p><strong>Compact Build and Muscularity:</strong> French Bulldogs have a compact, muscular body, which contributes to heat retention. They have a limited surface area for heat dissipation, making them more susceptible to overheating.</p>

<p><strong>Energetic Nature:</strong> French Bulldogs are playful and energetic, and this enthusiasm can lead to overheating, especially during intense activities in warm weather.</p>

<p><strong>Obesity Risks: </strong>French Bulldogs are prone to obesity, which can exacerbate their heat sensitivity. Maintaining a healthy weight is crucial in managing their susceptibility to overheating.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_7da1624fad234d04b30a580cfbc08bb7~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="French Bulldog daycare" alt="French bulldog daycare services"></figure><p><strong>Signs of Overheating in French Bulldogs</strong></p>

<p>Look out for the following signs that indicate your French Bulldog may be overheating:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Excessive panting or difficulty breathing</li>
  <li>Rapid heart rate</li>
  <li>Drooling, weakness, or collapse</li>
  <li>Seizures, vomiting, or diarrhea</li>
  <li>Elevated body temperature (above 104°F)</li>
</ul><p>
<strong>Preventing Overheating in French Bulldogs</strong></p>

<p><strong>Hydration is Key:</strong> Always provide access to fresh, cool water. On walks or trips, invest in a dog water bottle to keep your Frenchie hydrated. What helps is to have a ready to use travel water bottle for your pet when needed. Like this one "<a href="https://amzn.to/3G5tXYi" target="_blank" >ANPETBEST Dog Water Bottle</a>."</p>

<p><strong>Seek Shade and Avoid Direct Sunlight: </strong>While outdoors, ensure your pup has access to shaded areas, especially during peak sunlight hours.</p>

<p><strong>Cooling Mats for Instant Relief:</strong> Utilize cooling mats, which provide immediate comfort for your overheated French Bulldog both indoors and outdoors.</p>

<p><strong>Time Exercise Wisely:</strong> Schedule walks and playtime during cooler parts of the day, like early morning or late evening, to prevent overheating.</p>

<p><strong>Invest in a Dog Pool:</strong> A dog pool can be a delightful way for your French Bulldog to cool off on hot days. Always supervise them while they're in the water.</p>

<p><strong>Use Cooling Vests:</strong> Cooling vests are specially designed to regulate body temperature in hot weather and can be very effective for French Bulldogs.</p>

<p><strong>No Parked Cars, Ever:</strong> Never leave your French Bulldog in a parked car, as the temperature inside can rapidly escalate and become life-threatening.</p>

<p><strong>Provide a Cool Indoor Haven:</strong> If it's too hot outside, keep your French Bulldog indoors in an air-conditioned room.</p>

<p><strong>Watch Their Weight:</strong> A healthy diet and exercise routine will help maintain your Frenchie's weight, reducing their risk of overheating.</p>

<p><strong>Regular Vet Check-ups:</strong> Regular vet visits can help detect any health issues that might contribute to your Frenchie's heat sensitivity. If you are having a hard time booking an appointment, looking for a veterinarian, or prefer the comfort of your home. Try <a href="https://the-vets.sjv.io/R56Q17" target="_blank" ><u>"The Vets"</u></a>.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_8c928f3ba6f84c4caa20c06eb1a1df33~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_562,h_700,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="The Vets" alt="Advertising the vets. A mobile veterinarian services."></figure><p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>
By following these ten essential tips, you can protect your French Bulldog from overheating and ensure they enjoy a safe and happy summer. Remember, your proactive approach and attentive care are instrumental in keeping your Frenchie cool, comfortable, and healthy throughout the warm weather. Prioritize their well-being, and you'll be rewarded with many delightful moments and endless puppy love. Stay cool, Frenchie lovers!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[                  How to Potty Train Your French Bulldog]]></title><description><![CDATA[ How to Potty Train Your French Bulldog]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/how-to-potty-train-your-french-bulldog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">64c4a2bca4733e7d39901110</guid><category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 05:37:45 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_c8bf6d0ffe16467ba6adad285e3e2347~mv2.webp/v1/fit/w_729,h_486,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>If you're reading this, chances are you've recently welcomed a French Bulldog into your home. Congratulations! You're now the proud parent of a breed known for its charm, wit, and...well, stubbornness. But don't worry, we've got you covered. In this blog post, we'll guide you through the process of potty training your French Bulldog with a dash of humor. So, grab your poop bags, put on your most forgiving pair of shoes, and let's dive in!</em></strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_c8bf6d0ffe16467ba6adad285e3e2347~mv2.webp/v1/fit/w_729,h_486,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Understand Your Frenchie</strong></p>

<p><strong>The Stubborn Streak</strong></p><ul>
  <li>French Bulldogs are known for their stubbornness. They can be real little Napoleon Bonaparte when they want to be. But remember, you're the pack leader here.</li>
  <li>Consistency is key. Don't give in to those puppy dog eyes when they refuse to go potty outside. Stick to your guns, and your Frenchie will eventually get the message.
</li>
</ul><p><strong>The Need for Regular Breaks</strong></p><ul>
  <li>French Bulldogs have small bladders. This means they need to go more often than other breeds. So, be prepared for frequent bathroom breaks.</li>
  <li>Puppies especially need to go often - usually every 2-3 hours. That's right, even at night. So, say goodbye to uninterrupted sleep for a while.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Potty Training Steps</strong></p>

<p><strong>Step 1: Establish a Routine</strong></p><ul>
  <li>Dogs thrive on routine. Set specific times for meals, playtime, and potty breaks. Your Frenchie will soon start to associate these times with their corresponding activities.</li>
  <li>Remember, after every meal, nap, or play session, it's time for a potty break!</li>
</ul><p>
<strong>Step 2: Choose a Potty Spot</strong></p><ul>
  <li>Choose a specific spot outside for your Frenchie to do their business. This will help them understand where it's acceptable to go.</li>
  <li>Whenever it's potty time, lead them to this spot. And yes, this means even in the rain, snow, or zombie apocalypse.</li>
</ul><p>
<strong>Step 3: Use a Cue Word or Phrase</strong></p><ul>
  <li>Choose a cue word or phrase like "go potty" to signal to your Frenchie that it's time to go.</li>
  <li>Use this phrase every time they're about to go, and they'll soon start to associate it with the act.</li>
</ul><p>
<strong>Step 4: Reward Success</strong></p><ul>
  <li>When your Frenchie successfully goes potty outside, throw a mini party! Give them treats, praise, or playtime. This will reinforce positive behavior.</li>
  <li>On the flip side, if they have an accident indoors, don't scold or punish them. Instead, calmly clean it up and continue with the training. </li>
  <li>These are healthy treats that will help with the process: <a href="https://amzn.to/3eEqHqo" target="_blank" ><u><strong>Soft Puppy Bites</strong></u></a> </li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>

<p>In conclusion, potty training your French Bulldog may feel like you're trying to conquer a small, furry, stubborn France. But with patience, consistency, and a good sense of humor, you'll soon have a house-trained Frenchie. And remember, every little success is a step closer to a poop-free living room! With dedication and love, you and your new companion will build a strong bond that will last a lifetime. Happy training! Learn more about how you can be the best French Bulldog owner you can be with our blogs: <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/blog" target="_blank" ><strong><u>Northcalfrenchies Blogs</u></strong></a> </p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Are You A French Bulldog Person?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Answers to questions that will help you find out if a french bulldog is for you.]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/are-you-a-french-bulldog-person</link><guid isPermaLink="false">64baf2a327f76bb974c5ff7e</guid><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 21:27:51 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_90c7db03de434ba898e5f2936c6ec31c~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_667,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>This is a great question for someone who is thinking about getting a french bulldog or already has one. </em></strong></p>

<p><strong><em>If you haven’t yet done so, take the Are You A French Bulldog Person Quiz before continuing to read this blog.</em></strong></p>

<p>“<a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/are-you-a-frenchie-person" target="_blank" >,<u>Are You A French Bulldog Person</u></a>” </p> <p><strong><em>Check Your Quiz Questions and Answers. </em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>This will help you understand your score and if Frenchies are for You!</em></strong></p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_90c7db03de434ba898e5f2936c6ec31c~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_667,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Do you plan to go on long distance runs with your dog?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: No</strong></p>

<p><strong>No, French Bulldogs are not well-suited for long-distance runs due to their brachycephalic (short-nosed) structure, which can lead to breathing difficulties. They prefer shorter walks and moderate exercise to stay healthy and happy.</strong></p>


<p><strong>Are you looking for an inside or outside pet?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: Both</strong></p>

<p><strong>French Bulldogs do great as both inside and outside pets. As long as it is not too cold or too hot outside they love the fresh air and the free space to roam around. They are great in the house too, the perfect size, minimal shedding, their love to nap just about anywhere, and not much barking gives them the title as "Apartment Dogs".</strong></p>

<p>
<strong>Will it be a problem if your dog is the center of attention?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: No</strong></p>
<p><strong>
Dogs often enjoy being in the spotlight and receiving love and attention from their owners and others. As long as the attention is positive and doesn't lead to any behavioral issues, it can actually strengthen the bond between you and your furry friend.</strong></p>


<p><strong>Do you want a friend that snuggles with you and never wants to leave your side?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: Yes</strong></p>
<p>
<strong>Absolutely! French Bulldogs are known for their affectionate nature, making them wonderful companions that love to snuggle and stay close to their owners, providing constant warmth and companionship.</strong></p>


<p><strong>Will it bother you if your dog Snores, Snorts, and Farts?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: No</strong></p>

<p><strong>No, these quirks are common and accepted among French Bulldog owners, adding to the breed's charm and humor. Their adorable snoring, snorting, and occasional flatulence are endearing traits that are embraced with affection and understanding.</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_c4777b3855fc4072b44713148ef5b0f3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>
<strong>Are you a person who walks their dog in really HOT or COLD weather?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: No</strong></p>
<p><strong>
No, French Bulldogs are not typically walked in really hot or cold weather due to their temperature sensitivity, particularly because of their short snouts, which can make it challenging for them to cope with extreme temperatures.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Read our Blog on this topic:</strong></p> <p>
</p>
<p><strong>What fur length do you like most?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: Short Fur</strong></p>

<p><strong>With a French Bulldog, short fur is often favored as it helps to regulate their body temperature, keeping them comfortable in various climates. They are not none for excessive shedding.</strong></p>

<p><strong>Read our Blog on this topic:</strong></p>
 <p><strong>Do you want a dog that can swim?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: No</strong></p>

<p><strong>French Bulldogs are not natural swimmers due to their brachycephalic (short-nosed) facial structure and body formation, which can make swimming difficult and potentially dangerous. </strong></p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_fe8b6e5377c7430698fdc90b3ff9f915~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_807,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>
</p>
<p><strong>What size are you most comfortable with for an adult dog breed?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: 15-35 Pounds</strong></p>

<p><strong>A size range of 15-35 pounds is often preferred for adult dog breeds, including French Bulldogs, as it strikes a balance between manageability and companionship.</strong></p>
<p>

</p>
<p><strong>Will it be a problem for you, if your dog is really stubborn?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: No</strong></p>

<p><strong>The French Bulldog's stubborn nature comes from the bulldog family tree and is embraced by owners who value their endearing and devoted personalities, fostering a strong and loving connection.</strong></p>

<p>
<strong>What kind of ears do you prefer?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: Big</strong></p>
<p>
<strong>French Bulldogs are known for their bat ears, which are a defining characteristic of the breed, lending them a unique and utterly charming look that captures the hearts of dog lovers everywhere.</strong></p>
<p>

</p>
<p><strong>Do you want a dog with a long tail?</strong></p>
<p><strong>Answer: No</strong></p>

<p><strong>No, a long tail is not preferred for a French Bulldog, as they are known for having naturally short and often screw-shaped tails, which are characteristic of the breed.</strong></p>



<p><strong>Learn More about French Bulldogs on our French Bulldog FAQs Page.</strong></p>

 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[               How Much Exercise Does a French Bulldog Need?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn more about the needed exercise for a french bulldog and how to do it.]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/how-much-exercise-does-a-french-bulldog-need</link><guid isPermaLink="false">64baecba9b3b5c9f11052b07</guid><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 21:02:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_18c1ed1663f648f08993abaa5919aa71~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_18c1ed1663f648f08993abaa5919aa71~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><em><strong>Are you ready to get those little French Bulldog legs moving? Sure, they may have a face only a mother could love, but don't let that fool you! These adorable pups need their daily dose of exercise to keep them feeling fabulous. So, let's dive into the playful world of French Bulldog fitness and find out just how much exercise these little fellas really need!</strong></em></p>


<p><strong>Finding the Perfect Balance: </strong></p>

<p><em><strong>When it comes to exercise, French Bulldogs are like that friend who enjoys a good workout but also loves their cheat day treats. So, how much exercise do these little nuggets need? Well, buckle up, folks, because they require around<u> 60 minutes </u>of exercise each day. That's right, an hour of fun and frolic to keep them fit, happy, and ready to conquer the world!</strong></em></p>

<p><em><strong>Treats can be a great way to motivate any dog including Frenchies.</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>Try the </strong></em><a href="https://amzn.to/3eEqHqo" target="_blank" ><em><strong><u>Wellness Soft Puppy Bites</u></strong></em></a> </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_f63f36540ee44e0dbc03eaa4cfbcaa6a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_834,h_942,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>The Mighty Hour of Fun: Activities for French Bulldogs</strong></p>

<p><strong><em>Now, let's dive into the exciting world of French Bulldog workouts! Here are some pawsome activities to get your Frenchie's tail waggin':</em></strong></p>

<p><strong>Sniff 'n' Stroll:</strong> Take your French Bulldog on a leisurely walk around the block, letting them explore the scents and sights of the neighborhood. It's like their own personal version of "Sniff and the City"!</p>

<p><strong>Turbo Playdates</strong>: Set up playdates with their furry friends to unleash their boundless energy. Whether it's a game of chase, a tug-of-ear war, or a friendly wrestling match, it's time to let those floppy ears flap in the wind!</p>

<p><strong>Brainy Games:</strong> Challenge your Frenchie's intellect with puzzle toys and treat-dispensing games. It's like CrossFit for their minds, keeping them entertained and mentally sharp.</p>

<p><strong>Aqua Adventures: </strong>Did you know that French Bulldogs can be water aficionados? Supervised swimming sessions or a splash in a doggy pool can make exercise a splash-tastic experience. Just remember to bring a towel for the inevitable wet Frenchie shake!</p>

<p><strong>PetSafe Automatic Tennis Ball Launcher: </strong>If your tired but your furry friend still wants to play. Try this <a href="https://amzn.to/3EL2Cfl" target="_blank" ><u>PetSafe Automatic Tennis Ball Launcher</u></a>! Your Frenchie can chase the tennis ball and drop it into the launcher. A few seconds later they are chasing the tennis ball again. They can give chase until they get all their energy out!</p>

<p>Remember, while an hour of exercise is vital for French Bulldogs, it's essential to keep an eye on their body language and overall well-being. Frenchies can be over-enthusiastic and prone to overheating due to their adorable brachycephalic features. Their flatter faces and shortened noses make it more challenging for them to regulate their body temperature. So, exercise them during cooler parts of the day, provide plenty of water, and take breaks when needed.

<strong>Signs of Lack of Exercise: </strong></p>
<p>
<strong><em>If you find yourself pondering whether your French Bulldog is getting enough exercise, there are several telltale signs that can help you gauge their activity level. One clear indication of a lack of exercise is increased restlessness or hyperactivity, often exhibited through destructive behavior or excessive barking. Additionally, weight gain or difficulty maintaining a healthy weight might point to insufficient physical activity. Your Frenchie may also become easily bored or exhibit attention-seeking behaviors when they aren't adequately stimulated. Lack of exercise can impact their overall demeanor, leading to a decrease in their usual cheerful and playful attitude. To ensure your furry companion's well-being, it's essential to observe their behavior and consider incorporating more exercise into their routine if necessary.</em></strong></p>

<p><strong>The Perks of Being a Frenchie Fitness Fanatic</strong></p>

<p><strong>Regular exercise not only keeps your French Bulldog fit but also helps prevent obesity, boosts cardiovascular health, and enhances mental stimulation. Plus, there's nothing quite like watching those squishy faces light up with joy as they zoom around like tiny, wiggly tornadoes!</strong></p>

<p><strong>There are other factors that play when caring for your frenchies' health and well being. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Check out our other blogs on topics such as:</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/do-french-bulldogs-shed" target="_blank" ><strong><u>Do Frenchies Shed?</u></strong></a> </p>

<p><a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/is-it-to-hot-for-your-french-bulldog" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>Is It too hot or cold for your Frenchie?</u></strong></a></p>

<p><a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/is-your-puppy-eating-poop" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>Is Your Frenchie Eating Poop?</u></strong></a> </p>


<p>
<strong>Wrapping Up the Woof-tastic Workout</strong></p>

<p><strong><em>Now that you're equipped with all the doggy exercise knowledge, it's time to embark on your French Bulldog fitness journey. Remember, finding the balance between fun and safety is the key to a healthy and happy Frenchie. So, get ready to wiggle, waddle, and sweat (not too much, though) while you and your furry friend create lifelong memories on your exercise adventures. Let's get those little legs pumpin' and those tails waggin'- it's time for the French Bulldog fitness revolution!</em></strong></p>


 <figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is Your Puppy Eating Poop?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn why french bulldogs eat poop and what to do about it.]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/is-your-puppy-eating-poop</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63db564e5a8a28e1c85e4290</guid><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 06:36:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_775d27d42081477b80472003c79d65ac~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_400,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_775d27d42081477b80472003c79d65ac~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_400,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>

<p>One of the strangest experiences my wife (Alina) and I had with our french bulldog (Honey), was when she ate her own poop. We noticed that after she would poop, then she would turn around and eat it. At first we thought she was broken. After much research and a lot of attempts we were thrilled to see that she no longer eats her own poop. This is what we learned with our Frenchie.</p>

<p>There’s a scientific name for this poop-eating habit— coprophagia (kop-ruh-fey-jee-uh) and also there are both behavioral and physiological reasons why some dogs view poop as a delicacy. This is common with puppies, essentially french bulldogs. </p>

<p><strong>Here are a few reasons why they do this:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>They learned it from mom</li>
  <li>Boredom or stress </li>
  <li>Not getting enough food </li>
  <li>Not getting enough nutrients</li>
  <li>It's just a habit </li>
  <li>A need for attention</li>
</ul>
<p>There is hope. These are ways that you can help your puppy beat this poop eating problem. It might feel and seem like a hopeless endeavor. This will take time and a  lot of patience. Believe me, I know. Trying to pick up the poop before your puppy eats it may seem impossible, but let's get to the root of the problem. This problem is not only nasty, it leads to digestive problems and exposes them to parasites and harmful bacteria.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_b647848d433c40c2a455dc8beb72d12a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Nutrition Is Key</strong></p>

<p>The first thing we did and you can do this too, is to check the ingredients in your puppies' food. As your puppy grows, there are needed components in the food that help with this. If the food has many fillers then your puppy is looking for other ways of getting what their growing bodies need. Sadly they resort to eating their own poop. </p>

<p>Adult stool eaters may have a deficiency in hydrochloric acid. One possible solution is introducing apple cider vinegar to their food. You may add about one teaspoon of vinegar directly into food per 25 pounds of body weight. Another digestive aid is raw zucchini. Raw zucchini would be a good first choice.</p>
<p>Here are some products I would recommend.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://amzn.to/3Fq6SiA" target="_blank" >,<u>Skin & Coat by Natural Dog Company</u></a></li>
  <li><a href="https://amzn.to/3IzITiO" target="_blank" >,<u>Probiotic Bites by Zesty Paws</u></a></li>
  <li><a href="https://amzn.to/3FWKdvT" target="_blank" >,<u>Multivitamin by Natural Dog Company </u></a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Breaking The Habit</strong></p>

<p>I noticed that puppies usually poop 10-15 minutes after they eat. It’s important to see and understand the behavior behind the eating of the poop. Being there while they are in the action will help stop the habit. By calling them, making a noise, or tapping your foot can distract them from their usual routine of turning around and eating their poop. This will cause them to change their action to doing something else. Over time you will see how they will not mind the poop so much but will find something else to do.</p>
<p>Here are some treats that can help refocus your Frenchie’s attention.</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://amzn.to/3eEqHqo" target="_blank" >,<u>Soft Puppy Bites</u></a></li>
  <li><a href="https://amzn.to/3vIzVKn" target="_blank" >,<u>Zuke’s Mini</u></a></li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_2a473d5f10f84857ac90083146d29aef~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p><strong>Taste Aversion Treatment</strong></p>

<p>There is another way to approach this problem. Making the poop not as appetizing as the puppy currently finds it to be. Once the puppy puts the poop in its mouth and then finds it to be not what it was before can be a big turn off for them. JJ Diaz of <a href="http://plus.google.com/108329379379397492139/about?hl=en" target="_blank" >,<u>Animal Crackers</u></a> also has a tip up his sleeve to help the dog that eats stool. If everything else is in tip-top shape, “the way you break that habit is to feed him pineapple snacks. It messes up the flavor with acidity and your dog stops eating it 90% of time.”</p>


<p>Taste Aversion suggestions:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://amzn.to/3wLse7s" target="_blank" >,<u>Naturvet</u></a></li>
  <li><a href="https://amzn.to/3Rs7RFL" target="_blank" >,<u>Zesty Paws</u></a></li>
</ul>


<p>This is a common problem for Frenchies. Take it one step at a time. I am speaking from experience, there is hope with this poop eating problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[New Frenchie, Now What?]]></title><description><![CDATA[There is nothing like the feeling of getting a new puppy! When the day comes and you are on your way home with your new furry family...]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/new-puppy-now-what</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6375e3d34c2f879f2ec3f58a</guid><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 07:47:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_5e51aa56b9504f619b481ddf8848347f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_5e51aa56b9504f619b481ddf8848347f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>There is nothing like the feeling of getting a new puppy! When the day comes and you are on your way home with your new furry family member; this is where reality hits. Hopefully you read our blog about <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/getting-a-french-bulldog-puppy" target="_blank" >,<u>getting a new Frenchie</u></a> to help you prepare for this moment. In this blog, we put together a list of things to better prepare you and make this transition in your life as smooth as possible. </p>

<p>This is an exciting experience for us but can be a stressful one for the puppy. They are going to a place they don’t know, with a person they don't know. But there is hope. What can help is something they are familiar with such as a toy or a blanket and lots of love, their separation anxiety will pass.</p>

<p>It's important to keep the puppy pad training going as soon as possible. It depends on how disciplined you are. The puppy will be overwhelmed with the new smells, people, and environment. It is best to find a place to keep him/her with puppy pads, bed, water, and food bowl for most parts of the day for them to adjust. After a week or so the barrier can be taken away and the puppy can roam around the house and then come back to their place to go potty. They usually go potty 10-15 minutes after they eat. As they get older they can go to the bathroom outside when you let them out. </p><p>Working with many French Bulldog Breeders and Owners, along with owning French Bulldogs, here is a list of things we would recommend you get for your puppy. You can use it as a checklist at the pet store or order directly from Amazon. <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/frenchbulldogessentials" target="_blank" >Frenchie Essentials Checklist</a></p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_4cd21ba0e306471695ac442d167a3be1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Remember puppies are like children and get their noses into everything. I wouldn’t recommend that they play with dogs/cats that are not yours or go outside until they are 15 weeks and/or have all their vaccinations. </p>

<p>It is important to know what food brand your puppy is eating and to have some ready when needed. If you choose to go with your own brand of food, make sure to blend the food he/she is eating. Half of the old food and half of the new food for a few days. The difference in nutrition, sodium, and quick food change can have a bad effect on the stomach. You will need to monitor their eating and adjust as they get older. Their stool will become wet when they are eating too much or they can throw up the kibble when it expands their stomach. Wet food is ok but not too much because the stool will become wet. </p>

<p>Treats are a good form of positive reinforcement. Take it one step at a time. See how the treat affects your puppy’s stomach. If he or she is having wet stool for a long period of time, it’s time to try a different type of treat.</p>

<p>The raw food diet is always the best choice but it can be pricey and time consuming. There are lots of great recipes online. There are also pre-made raw foods that can be delivered to your home. We recommend “<a href="https://www.myollie.com/?irclickid=QLmWJg2PKzbXTcKyJ103-WXbUkAyX%3AQPuX1o2I0&#38;irgwc=1&#38;ir_campaignid=12309&#38;ir_adid=890556&#38;ir_partnerid=2718839&#38;partner=Northcalfrenchies&#38;utm_source=impact&#38;utm_medium=affiliate&#38;offer_code=OLLIE50S" target="_blank" >,<u>Ollie</u></a>”</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_5c4282c0c0844d9097a56b3ec8b209d5~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_768,h_512,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p>The best temperature for your new puppy is between 73-76 degrees. </p>

<p>Just a heads up. Puppies have a sensitive stomach, so too much play on the grass can cause a rash. </p>

<p>It is a good idea to schedule a veterinarian visit for a second look to clear his or her health. They may need some vaccinations and a parasite check. This is a great opportunity for them to experience riding in a car, meeting and interacting with new people. </p>

<p>Pet Insurance is very important at this age. Here is a link to a pet insurance where you can get a free quote and see if it works for you. <a href="https://pinpaws.sjv.io/OrmaWP" target="_blank" ><u>Pin Paws Pet Insurance.</u></a> </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_dda4f11f40984d4e833dcd7b6796718d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p>In any case we can't be prepared for everything and that’s ok. Things will come up and you can take it one step at a time. After a week or so you will become a natural. We offer lifetime pet care. If you have any questions or concerns do not hesitate. Call, text, email, or facetime us!</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_a4ad5d0be60e40fd88dc38b235c355d1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Do All Pet Owners Need Pet Insurance?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Every pet owner comes across this question. Since we can’t predict the future and pet behavior can be unpredictable; is it safer to get...]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/do-all-pet-owners-need-pet-insurance</link><guid isPermaLink="false">636193e3202579aa51204b3a</guid><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 21:49:19 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_dda4f11f40984d4e833dcd7b6796718d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every pet owner comes across this question. Since we can’t predict the future and pet behavior can be unpredictable; is it safer to get pet insurance or can we deal with the cost on our own. Learn more about french bulldogs and what you can expect! <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/full-facts-about-french-bulldogs" target="_blank" >,<u>Fun Facts About French Bulldogs</u></a> Here are things to consider before making this decision for you and your family.</p>

<p>Pet insurance is just that. Having the finances to cover the cost for unexpected accidents my french bulldog has or can endure. If I am able and disciplined to start putting money aside to pay those needed expenses for my Frenchie, then in my opinion pet insurance is not for me. Hopefully that day never comes, but if it does then I have a safety net to look for when the bills start adding up. Also, the money I saved up can be used for other things if my pet ends up not needing it. </p>

<p>On the other hand if I don’t have the discipline and I am not saving money, then I am in big trouble when my french bulldog needs me the most. Not saving money or having pet insurance will cause me to lose a lot more than I would think. That’s why it's important to start planning now rather than later. Doing my research on pet insurance and the one I would recommend is <a href="https://pinpaws.sjv.io/OrmaWP" target="_blank" ><u>PinPaws Pet insurance.</u></a> Get a free quote and see if they are the right fit for you? </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_dda4f11f40984d4e833dcd7b6796718d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Common reasons for pet visits:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Routine check-ups</li>
  <li>Heartworm testing</li>
  <li>Caring for your pet’s ears</li>
  <li>Fighting fleas</li>
  <li>The fecal exams</li>
  <li>Dental cleaning</li>
  <li>Allergy tests</li>
  <li>Spay and neuter</li>
  <li>Geriatric screenings </li>
  <li>Pet vaccinations</li>
  <li>Diagnostic testing</li>
  <li>Emergency visit</li>
</ul>

<p>Even though anything can happen anywhere with Frenchies, the odds greatly decrease when it comes to the daily lifestyle. If we don’t go on trips much, aside from daily walks then the odds can be in our favor. Familiarity is great and it leaves little room for the unknown. But if we go to dog parks, beach trips, family gatherings, community events, hikes and so on; this will make it hard to keep my Frenchie from running into unwanted bodily harm. </p>

<p>Life is full of surprises and Frenchies are known for getting their noses into unwanted areas. If we are able to save up and prepare for the worst then pet insurance isn't for us. But if we live life on the edge and don’t save for a future accident then we can set ourselves up for financial and emotional trauma. I hope this blog will help you make the needed steps that will benefit you and your furry family member.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Getting a French Bulldog Puppy?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Questions to ask ourselves before getting a new puppy. Are you ready? Is your home ready? Is it the right breeder? Is it the right puppy?...]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/getting-a-french-bulldog-puppy</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63524f67cd616795ba9b997b</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 08:01:30 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_0be09521ccc44d58b7a23cec29780550~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Questions to ask ourselves before getting a new puppy. </strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Are you ready?</li>
  <li>Is your home ready?</li>
  <li>Is it the right breeder?</li>
  <li>Is it the right puppy?</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_0be09521ccc44d58b7a23cec29780550~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Are you ready?</strong></p>

<p>Yes puppies are cute, adorable, fun, and so much more. French Bulldog puppies are the cutest in my opinion. Puppies bring so much joy to the home. They are great for social emotional health, changing up the home dynamic, relieving stress, encouraging an active lifestyle, and making us more happy in life. Studies show that people with pets live longer. Puppies are all those things, but they come with much responsibility. </p>

<p>Here are a few questions to ask yourself before making the big step. We all hear about impulsive purchases and buyer's remorse. Not only does it have a negative effect on you and your family, but it also has a negative effect on the puppy. These are the questions to think about before scheduling an appointment to see a puppy. </p>
<ul>
  <li>Are you physically, emotionally, and mentally ready for a new furry family member?</li>
  <li>Do you have the time?</li>
  <li>Can you afford it?</li>
  <li>Do you have someone to watch him or her when you are not able to?</li>
  <li>Will they be able to bond with your current pet/s?</li>
  <li>How will you deal with behavioral issues?</li>
  <li>Are you ready for potty training?</li>
  <li>Raw food diet or kibble?</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/do-french-bulldogs-shed" target="_blank" ><u>Are you ready for shedding?</u></a></li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Is your home ready?</strong></p>

<p>Puppies like to get their noses into everything. It’s up to us as good puppy parents to block off needed areas, move wires, take away things that can be chewed on and so on. To help you from playing catch up when the puppy is already at your home, these are great questions to ask and things to do.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Do you have the space?</li>
  <li>Do you have a vet selected?</li>
  <li>Will they be spayed or neutered?</li>
  <li>Is your home safe or suitable for a puppy?</li>
  <li>Are there plants or materials that are not safe for puppies in reach?</li>
  <li>Does your apartment complex or landlord allow pets? </li>
  <li>Is the temperature right?</li>
  <li>Do you have a designated place for the puppy?</li>
</ul>

<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TMtTzUp6ajk">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TMtTzUp6ajk</a><p><strong>Is it the right breeder?</strong></p>

<p>The breeder/owner is a big part in your Frenchie’s life. It's important to pick the right one for a smooth transition. We do our best to make sure that we build a relationship and ask the needed questions when it comes to Frenchie owners/breeders and breeding in general. In any case, it is always important to ask the right questions before getting your new furry family member.</p>

<p><strong>Breeder:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>How long have they been breeding?</li>
  <li>Do they provide vaccination and deworming treatment records?</li>
  <li>Has the puppy been seen by a veterinarian?</li>
  <li>Do they provide a health guarantee?</li>
  <li>Can they show parent pictures?</li>
  <li>What are the parents' ages?</li>
  <li>How much do the parents weigh?</li>
  <li>Have the parents had any physical or medical issues?</li>
  <li>What food does the puppy currently eat?</li>
  <li>What is the feeding schedule?</li>
  <li>Is the puppy in potty training?</li>
  <li>How does the puppy play with his or her siblings?</li>
  <li>What is the puppy's energy level?</li>
  <li>Ask for references from people who bought puppies from them before.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Previous owner:</strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>How long have they owned the Frenchie?</li>
  <li>Why are they rehoming him or her?</li>
  <li>Do they provide vaccination and deworming treatment records?</li>
  <li>Any connection with the breeder?</li>
  <li>How does the Frenchie act towards other dogs or pets?</li>
  <li>How are they with children?</li>
  <li>Where do they currently sleep?</li>
  <li>What is their feeding schedule?</li>
  <li>Are they potty trained?</li>
  <li>Are they Spayed or Neutered?</li>
</ul><p>Learn more about "<a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/rehomingprocess" target="_blank" ><u>NorthCalFrenchies Rehoming Process.</u></a>"</p>

<p><strong>Is it the right puppy?</strong></p>

<p>Over the years I have had a chance to help find homes for many Frenchies of all ages. It is a happy and sad experience. Happy because they are going to a new and loving home and sad because they are going away and now I will mostly see them in pictures as they grow up. My wife wants to keep all of them and my Frenchie “Honey” wants to play all day with them. The big question is: which one will be your puppy? How to decide? These questions will stand out when choosing a puppy.</p>
<ul>
  <li>What color?</li>
  <li>What gender?</li>
  <li>Energetic or calm?</li>
  <li>Slim or chubby?</li>
  <li>Big ears or small ears?</li>
  <li>Kisser or nibbler?</li>
  <li>Exotic or basic?</li>
  <li>One or two?</li>
  <li>Vocal or quiet?</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Sources:</strong></p><ul>
  <li><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSce14sncBAr5fVZV3znav0ECIMbIySkniqF-7FePcN-DC8e8g/viewform" target="_blank" ><u>Are you a Frenchie person quiz</u></a> </li>
  <li><a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/full-facts-about-french-bulldogs" target="_blank" ><u>Fun facts about French Bulldogs</u></a> </li>
  <li><a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/frenchbulldogcare" target="_blank" ><u>Frenchie Care</u></a> </li>
</ul>


<p>In any case, when looking for the right puppy a french bulldog is the way to go! Learn more in my “<a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/why-a-french-bulldog" target="_blank" ><u>why a French Bulldog blog</u></a>”. They are the full package and there is a reason why they are the second most popular dog in the United States. As you take the needed steps to welcome your new furry family member don't hesitate to call, text, email, or reach out to us on social media. "<a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/" target="_blank" ><u>Home Page</u></a>" We are always ready to answer any question or concern you may have.</p>


<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_2a473d5f10f84857ac90083146d29aef~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Do French Bulldogs Shed?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Quick Answer: If you are planning on keeping a pet in your house or apartment, chances are you have to deal with unwanted hair on your...]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/do-french-bulldogs-shed</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6344adb96bf508c2eda2467d</guid><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 23:49:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_e53457ad554a4eee8ef1bf41e20e7daf~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_720,h_733,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>NorthCalFrenchies</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Quick Answer:</strong></p>

<p><em>If you are planning on keeping a pet in your house or apartment, chances are you have to deal with unwanted hair on your floor or furniture: it’s just part of the package! In this blog I will do my best to help you keep the shedding as low as possible.</em></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_e53457ad554a4eee8ef1bf41e20e7daf~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_720,h_733,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>French Bulldogs and Shedding…</strong></p>

<p>You might think Frenchies with their short and smooth coats don’t shed much. The truth is actually far from that: most Frenchies tend to shed all year long and even more so during warmer months.</p>
<p>French Bulldogs have short fur and compared to other breeds, their shedding is not as noticeable. I have a cream female frenchie (Honey) that stays in the house for most part of the day. To be honest we don’t notice her fur on the furniture or on the floor. But when we wear darker clothing we can see the fur. My wife and I joke around when we go places without Honey saying that we brought some of her with us. </p>


<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_0a5ce6e94a4448178ec7134e2c2a01b7~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Way Too Much Shedding?</strong></p>

<p><strong>Change In Weather</strong></p>

<p>There are times in the year when there is a transition from hot to cold or cold to hot months, we notice more shedding than usual. This is common for dogs in general and your frenchie is not an exception. We all know frenchies do not do well in the heat or in cold temperatures (<a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/is-it-to-hot-for-your-french-bulldog" target="_blank" >,<u>Read my blog about this topic</u></a>), the shedding or adding of fur will help them adjust. Here are a few tips in keeping the shedding low during this time. </p>
<ul>
  <li>Brush them daily (<a href="https://amzn.to/3v8xxMk" target="_blank" >,<u>Recommended Brush</u></a>)</li>
  <li>Wash them often (<a href="https://amzn.to/3qP4fz7" target="_blank" >,<u>Recommended Shampoo</u></a>)</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_e00bbde8411543e28a56517cdde8a5e8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_922,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_afcfcdd73c63490289736cd468fafbef~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_952,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Needed Vitamins</strong></p>

<p>Your frenchie could be losing fur because of insufficient vitamins and minerals that they aren’t getting from their daily diet. Always look for a premium dog food with high protein content, and if one food doesn’t work out don’t stop searching until you find what works best for your fur baby. We all know the raw food diet is the best option. It does add up in cost, time, and energy but there is no way around it. As you consider your food options, there are multivitamins that can help give what your frenchie’s system needs. We use this for Honey and highly recommend it! <a href="https://amzn.to/3Fq6SiA" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>Natural Dog Company Skin & Coat Chews</u></strong></a></p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_9320aae56ab844719eb81574a402f1f1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_626,h_774,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Allergies</strong></p>

<p>Another thing that could cause excessive shedding in Frenchies is allergies. Whether it’s an ingredient in their food (like chicken), some sort of medicine or something in their environment (like a new detergent), your puppy may react to it by shedding if they are allergic. </p>

<p>Ask yourself these questions:</p>

<p><strong>#1</strong> The first thing is to see what has been changed recently: washing detergent, diet, or a new place you take him or her too?</p>
<p><strong>#2</strong> If you can’t think of anything, the best tip is to change to super premium hypoallergenic dry food.</p>
<p><strong>#3</strong> If that doesn’t help either, contact your vet, and they can prescribe needed medication.</p>

<p>Frenchies are amazing and we can’t live without them! One thing we will have to deal with is shedding. I hope these steps can help minimize the shedding and keep you and your frenchie happy! Check out our other <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/blog" target="_blank" >,<u>blogs</u></a> for more frenchie care or visit our frenchie <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/frenchbulldogcare" target="_blank" >,<u>care tab.</u></a> </p>

<p><strong>Join the Frenchie Family!</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_9af54f674647401ba90c3ea900bee931~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is It To Hot For Your French Bulldog?]]></title><description><![CDATA[As Spring slowly turns into Summer, dependent where you are in the world, Summer months can have a big effect on your French Bulldog....]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/is-it-to-hot-for-your-french-bulldog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6289a03a5f3909928e65c4e4</guid><category><![CDATA[Health]]></category><pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 02:42:13 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_1a8d75dbd0ad4b21b6f020f97a123655~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator></dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As Spring slowly turns into Summer, dependent where you are in the world, Summer months can have a big effect on your French Bulldog. They do their best to care for us in their own special way, and we can take the necessary steps to care for them. Because your Frenchie has a shorter snout, causing them to snore, snort, look adorable, and so much more, this also keeps them from cooling themselves off in hot places. ​​This face-style is known as brachycephalic–meaning it is a “short-nosed” breed. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_1a8d75dbd0ad4b21b6f020f97a123655~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>What does it look like when your French Bulldog is over heating?</strong></p>

<p>As a dog’s temperature rises, blood rushes to the surfaces of the tongue, gums, and membranes to help transfer excess heat. Dogs do not sweat like humans do, they can sweat from the paws and their mouth and nose transfer heat from the body. Frantic panting, lots of salivation, bright-red membranes, and labored breathing are clear warning signs that your dog is overheated and may quickly progress to a metabolic meltdown as his or her  temperature rises to over 106 F and he or she can no longer cool themselves. This fan with a spray bottle can come in handy during these dyer moments.  <a href="https://amzn.to/3MEtHTw" target="_blank" ><u>Deluxe Handheld Battery Powered Water Misting Fan</u></a> </p>
<p>Brachycephalic dogs—with shorter, pushed-in muzzles, shortened facial bones, and noses that are pushed in and upward—tend to be more heat-sensitive, and their airways can be less efficient at moving air in and out of the lungs and thus more susceptible to overheating. Grebe warns, “Anything that causes brachycephalic dogs to breathe harder places additional stress on their airways, whether it is overheating on a hot day, excitement that causes panting, or exercise that increases the oxygen demand of their muscles, requiring more strenuous breathing.” </p>

<p><strong>Two areas to watch out for during hot days.</strong></p>

<p><strong>1. Walking your French Bulldog on hot asphalt.</strong></p>

<p>When the air temperature is at these levels the asphalt has been measured at this temperature.</p>
<p><strong>Temperature                                      Asphalt</strong></p>

<p>77 Degrees 					125 Degrees</p>
<p>86 Degrees 					135 Degrees </p>
<p>87 Degrees					143 Degrees </p>

<p>At 125 degrees, skin destruction can occur in 60 seconds. An egg can fry in 5 minutes at 131 degrees. </p>

<p>The best way to check if the asphalt temperature is safe for your FRench Bulldog is to press the back of your hand firmly against the asphalt for 7 seconds to verify if it will be comfortable for him or her. </p>

<p><strong>2. Leaving you Frenchie in the car during a hot day.</strong></p>

<p>We would never recommend to leave your Frenchie in a car during a hot day (Even if your windows are cracked open)! These are the temperature comparisons between temperature outside and temperature in the car.</p>
<p><strong>Outside Your Vehicle</strong>			       <strong>Inside Your Vehicle</strong></p>
<p>70 Degrees 						95 Degrees </p>
<p>75 Degrees						101 Degrees </p>
<p>80 Degrees						110 Degrees </p>
<p>85 Degrees						117 Degrees</p>
<p>90 Degrees 						124 Degrees </p>

<h2><strong>How to Avoid Your Dog Overheating</strong></h2><ul>
  <li>Ensure that your dog has fresh water and shade, with short periods outside in hot weather. Check out a handy togo water bottle for your pet! <a href="https://amzn.to/3G5tXYi" target="_blank" ><u>Dog Bottle</u></a> </li>
  <li>Acclimate your dog to hot weather gradually and don’t exercise him on hot, humid days. Conditioned sporting dogs, even water retrievers, can overheat if the water is warm.</li>
  <li>Make sure your home is cooled on warm days. Install a temperature alarm in your motor home, van, and house that dials your cell phone automatically. Dogs have been lost when air conditioners or power failed unbeknown to the owners.</li>
  <li>Don’t place a crated dog where there is inadequate ventilation in warm, stagnant air under tents or in poorly ventilated buildings.</li>
  <li>Carefully observe elderly dogs, those that are chronically ill, or pets with respiratory inefficiency.</li>
  <li>Be vigilant with hairdryers anytime, especially cage dryers.</li>
  <li>Although a dog’s coat can provide insulation, double coats make a dog more vulnerable to overheating and dark coats absorb heat faster in the sun.</li>
  <li>Do not leave your French Bulldog in your car during a hot day.</li>
  <li>Make sure you are aware of the asphalt heat when walking your Frenchie.</li>
</ul>
<p>Learn more ways to care for your French Bulldog! Click "<a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/frenchbulldogcare" target="_blank" ><u>HERE</u></a>"</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fun Facts About French Bulldogs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn fun facts about french bulldogs.]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/full-facts-about-french-bulldogs</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62232396ed0128b37f2da7c7</guid><category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 08:49:32 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uRtSdwY49fM" length="0" type="video"/><dc:creator></dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uRtSdwY49fM">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uRtSdwY49fM</a>

<p><strong>FRENCH BULLDOGS ORIGINATED IN ENGLAND</strong></p>

<p>The French bulldog’s origins are traced to English roots. Lace makers in England were drawn to the smaller bulldog and would use them as lap warmers while they worked. When the lace industry moved to France, they took their dogs with them. There, the English bulldogs were bred with terriers to create bouledogues français, or French bulldogs. French bulldogs fall into the English Bulldog, Pug, Boston terrier, and American bully family tree. We prefer Frenchies out of the bunch. If you would like to show off that you are a Frenchie owner, wear some Frenchie Merch! <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/merch" target="_blank" >,<u>Norcalfrenchie Merch</u></a></p>

<p><strong>FRENCHIES ARE A TALKATIVE BREED</strong></p>

<p>French bulldogs might not bark much, but they do like to “talk.” Using a complex system of yawns, yips, and gargles, the dogs can convey the illusion of their own language. Sometimes they will even sing along with you in the car. Your Frenchies eyes do much talking if you pay close attention. You can communicate back to them using the same language of eye contact. When a dog gives you long, lingering eye contact, it’s a way of saying “I love you.” A recent study shows that oxytocin, the ‘love chemical,’goes up in both dogs and humans when they share a kind gaze. Watch your approach, though. Staring down a dog in a forceful manner can be a sign of aggression for your dog. If you are having a problem with your frenchie barking too much or behaviors that are not good, <a href="https://k9ti.org/free-workshop/?utm_source=referrer&#38;utm_medium=cpa&#38;utm_campaign=maxgonchar" target="_blank" >,<u>K9 Training Institute</u></a> is a great resource!</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_457b7a6cec76468e916ab794c5b51f3d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_600,h_373,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>FRENCH BULLDOGS ARE SENSITIVE</strong></p>

<p>As it turns out, French bulldogs are sensitive animals. If you think that your pet won’t be able to tell if you were criticizing him or her, think again. Dogs are known to be extremely good readers of human cues, so when you’re upset, your dog knows it. If you have a Frenchie that needs a lot of attention when it comes to discipline, it would be wise to not yell at them. French bulldogs will take your reprimanding quite seriously. If they do get yelled at, they’ll tend to mope around the house until they feel better or at least until they get positive reinforcement. The best way to deal with behavior issues or discipline issues is to employ positive reinforcement or encouragement. They’ll respond a lot better to those cues. The best Frenchie treats for positive reinforcement and training are <a href="https://amzn.to/3vIzVKn" target="_blank" >,<u>Zuke’s Mini Naturals.</u></a> </p>


<p><strong>FRENCH BULLDOG PUPPIES ARE BORN WITH FLOPPY EARS</strong></p>

<p>Because of the size of their ears, it takes some time for them to stand. Sometimes they begin to stand within a couple of weeks of birth, though the average age is about seven weeks old. Don’t despair if your puppy's ears are still not standing by then, just like humans, everyone develops at their own pace. There are many creative ways to help their ears stand faster but it is best to let them develop on their own. Keep their ears warm in cold weather with these cute <a href="https://amzn.to/3hriqYH" target="_blank" >,<u>dog hats</u></a>! </p>


<p><strong>THEY SNORT, SNORE, AND FART</strong></p>

<p>They fart a lot because their stomachs are very sensitive and because they eat so fast they ingest a lot of air. Furthermore, their farts smell pretty awful and they are silent “killers” but the fact that they startle themselves nearly every time by their own flatulence is absolutely hilarious! There is hope! There are ways to alleviate their gassiness; greek yogurt (no additives), canned pumpkin (no additives), and<a href="https://amzn.to/3Ma7ixk" target="_blank" >,<u> “Zesty Paws” Probiotic for Dogs.</u></a></p>


<p><strong>FRENCHIES HAVE TWO STYLES OF EARS </strong></p>

<p>Originally, French bulldogs had rose-shaped ears, similar to their larger relative, the English bulldog. English bulldog breeders much preferred the shape, but American breeders liked the unique bat ears. When a rose-eared bulldog was featured at the Westminster Kennel Club in 1897, American dog fanciers were very angry. If you are looking for small rose-shaped ears or big bat ears, <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/buy" target="_blank" >,<u>NorthCalFrenchies</u></a> works with many breeders and Frenchies owners in five states; California, Oregon, Washington, Idaho, and Nevada.   </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_c2d2b911d77e43b6bd2e9cf2af138ea3~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_640,h_640,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>CELEBRITIES LOVE FRENCHIES</strong></p>
<p>French Bulldogs are currently the most popular dogs in Hollywood and they are probably more popular among celebrities than any other dog breeds. They are an absolute hit! To some celebrities they almost come as some sort of fashion accessories, a “must have” if you want to leave the impression of prestige and they are just as popular among gentlemen. They have quite glamorous names too. Lady Gaga owns a girl called Miss Asia, Leonardo di Caprio named his dog Django and Hugh Jackman named his Frenchie Dali. Christina Ricci, Reese Witherspoon, Victoria and David Beckham, and Martha Stewart are also among proud French Bulldog owners. If you own a frenchie, time to look like it! <a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/merch" target="_blank" >,<u>Get some frenchie merch today!</u></a></p>
<p><strong>FRENCH BULLDOGS DON'T NEED A LOT OF EXERCISE</strong></p>

<p>Frenchies do need a daily walk to keep them healthy, but do not require a lot of exercises. They can take short walks throughout the day, as French Bulldogs are a brachycephalic breed. Meaning they have short snouts. Over exercising them, especially during warm weather may cause breathing problems. It’s also not a good idea to use collars for walks, a <a href="https://amzn.to/39jkejj" target="_blank" >,<u>harness</u></a> would be a better choice! </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_ee648ae959a5462184028ffde6f69ef4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p><strong>FRENCH BULLDOGS DON'T SHED VERY MUCH</strong></p><p>French Bulldogs do not shed very much because they have a fine, short, and smooth coat. However, during fall and winter, they lose their undercoats. A good <a href="https://amzn.to/3qP4fz7" target="_blank" >,<u>shampoo</u></a> and coat <a href="https://amzn.to/3MoXcZJ" target="_blank" >,<u>brush</u></a> can help during that time of fur loss.</p>

<p><strong>FRENCHIES SLEEP FOR A LONG TIME, AROUND 10 TO 13 HOURS A DAY</strong></p>

<p>Adult Frenchies usually sleep for around 10 to 13 hours per day. The rest of their time is spent running around, playing, eating, pooping, or just sitting in the living room. As French Bulldogs age, they require more hours of sleep because they tire more quickly. That’s why it's good to have a <a href="https://amzn.to/36Ym5Z8" target="_blank" >,<u>bed</u></a> that they can enjoy!  </p>
<h2><strong>Working with many French Bulldog Breeders and Owners, along with owning French Bulldogs, these are the top picks we would recommend for you and your Frenchies. </strong></h2><h3><a href="https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/frenchbulldogessentials" target="_blank" >,<u>Frenchie Essentials</u></a></h3><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_4cd21ba0e306471695ac442d167a3be1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Is Your Frenchie As Happy As You Are?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Frenchies have a way of changing the environment in the home. Their outgoing and curious nature with a strong will and loyalty to their...]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/is-your-frenchie-as-happy-as-you</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61afcdcd0434540016045998</guid><category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category><category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 21:13:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_2fecc8678bd8414180061f9a3a3d9093~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator></dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Frenchies have a way of changing the environment in the home. Their outgoing and curious nature with a strong will and loyalty to their owners give us a sense of joy and happiness. <a href="https://www.heart.org/en/healthy-living/healthy-bond-for-life-pets/do-dog-owners-live-longer" target="_blank" ><u>Studies</u></a> show over and over that those who have pets live a longer and healthier life. That's why Frenchies are often used as service animals for those that have a chronic illness or those that are recovering from trauma.</p>

<a href="https://youtu.be/Z3A7WaNtOaA">https://youtu.be/Z3A7WaNtOaA</a><p>But how do you know that your French Bulldog is happy? How do you know that your pet and member of your family is as happy as you are? Sadly they cant talk. They can’t express their feelings or thoughts through words. But dogs do communicate. They communicate with their facial expressions, grunts, barks, yelps, ears, eyes, body posture, fur elevation, tail semaphore, and more.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_49d3ded3fb4a48b9bb28ec1b312547d8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>As a dog owner, it's up to you to take the time to learn to communicate with your pet. Over time you will begin to have a dialog with your furry family member, not just have a monologue. French Bulldogs are smart dogs and they are used to routines and begin to know what we are thinking. There is a greater depth in the communication between a pet and their owner, it goes both ways.</p>

<p>Your Frenchie deserves the best CARE. Check out our page with all the needed resources to do so!</p> <figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_31e9ffbed00a44c5920d67a1057bbc25~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why A French Bulldog?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn why a french bulldog is the right choice for you.]]></description><link>https://www.northcalfrenchies.com/post/why-a-french-bulldog</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61a1d46515ab5b0016810047</guid><category><![CDATA[Adoption]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 06:50:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_b2043047d9d34e91adf110988a31779d~mv2_d_3024_4032_s_4_2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator></dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Out of the many dog breeds out there French Bulldogs take the first place! They are small, stubby, short snouted, bat-eared, skin full of rolls and wrinkles, snort, fart, snore, and so much more! These features make French Bulldogs the world's most popular small-dog breed, especially among city dwellers.</p>

<a href="https://youtu.be/6ns36r47Hk4">https://youtu.be/6ns36r47Hk4</a><p>I have found that their key alertness but low barking level, symmetrical bulldog look, low maintenance, calm, and playful temperament really makes them stand out. They love to be picked up and carried. Their keen ability to get along with other animals and children show their desire to belong. They are the perfect size, they don't knock everything over when they come in to the room and they are not so small where you accidentally sit on them and do lots of damage.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_fe8b6e5377c7430698fdc90b3ff9f915~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_807,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>
<p>That's why French Bulldogs are the second most popular dog breeds in America! </p>


<p>According to American Kennel Club: <a href="https://www.akc.org/expert-advice/dog-breeds/most-popular-dog-breeds-of-2021/" target="_blank" ><u>2021 Most Popular Dog Breed Full Ranking List</u></a> </p>

<p>Having a French Bulldog in the family and talking to other Frenchie parents, we would never go back on our decision and will continue to choose this breed out of the rest!</p>

<p>Take the "Are You A French Bulldog Person" Test to see if they are for you!</p>
 <figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/ff5b16_b2043047d9d34e91adf110988a31779d~mv2_d_3024_4032_s_4_2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>